

#### AI/MI ENGINEER · DATA SCIENTIST · AI/MI RESEARCHER AND DEVELOPER

English (Fluent) | Spanish (Fluent) | French (Advanced) | Dutch (Basic) | Hebrew (Basic)

□ (+420) 608-874-476 | ☑ j.ananias.hilario@gmail.com | 回 ananiask8 | 面 jose-hilario | Diploma Thesis

«If I am not for myself, who will be for me? And since I am for myself: what am I becoming? And if not now, when?»

# Summary.

I am an AI/ML Engineer with two years of experience in the field and five years of previous experience as a Software Developer. My main career interests are: 1) R&D on Deep Learning, Machine Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Game Theory and Combinatorial Optimization; 2) delivering end-to-end AI/ML solutions to production, and effectively evolving and maintaining them using MLOps principles.

I firmly believe in caring and in taking responsibility in life; every action we take should be for the sake of moving towards the right direction.

# **Experience**

Cogniware s.r.o.

ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE RESEARCHER AND DEVELOPER

*Prague, Czechia Apr 2020 - Present* 

• Responsibilities: Taking research outputs to production; pursuing an increased maturity of AI/ML projects; adoption of MLOps; AI/ML theory

- research (documenting, prototyping, data analysis, error analysis); Al/ML technologies research; mentoring

   Topics: Deep Learning (attention-based models, GANs...); Machine Learning (Random Forests, NMF, SVD...); Social Networks Analysis (homoge-
- neous/heterogeneous networks, community detection, structural types detection); Computer Vision (object detection and tracking, pedestrian attribute recognition, facial transformations); Fake News Detection (user interactions graph, NLP...); Anomaly Detection in Graphs.
- Technologies: PyTorch, TorchServe, Captum, PyTorch Ignite, Ax, Albumentations, Einops, MLflow, Scikit-learn, Hummingbird.

#### Czech Technical University in Prague (CTU)

Prague, Czechia

ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE RESEARCHER AND DEVELOPER

Sep 2019 - Apr 2020

· Algorithmic Game Theory and Machine Learning research; Integrating Deep Learning into Combinatorial Optimization algorithms.

Intellisys D. Corp Santiago, Dominican Republic

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Aug 2014 - Mar 2020

- Responsibilities: Fullstack development at Senior level; Design of training programs; Mentoring; Microservices; AB testing; Data migrations.
- Technologies: Webpack; nodejs; php; TypeScript; React; JavaScript ES6; HTML; CSS; Google AMP; Chrome Extensions.

### Mother and Teacher Pontifical Catholic University (PUCMM)

Santiago, Dominican Republic

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Aug 2012 - Jun 2013

• Design and analysis of: power electronics, linear control theory, embedded systems.

## **Education**

#### **Czech Technical University in Prague (CTU)**

Prague, Czechia

DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY - PHD: COMPUTER SCIENCE, UNFINISHED

2019 - 2020

• Topics: Deep Learning; Deep Reinforcement Learning; Algorithmic Game Theory; Multi-agent Systems.

#### **Czech Technical University in Prague (CTU)**

Prague, Czechia

MASTER OF SCIENCE - MS: ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE, 1.49 CZ GPA (3.38 US GPA)

2017 - 2019

• Topics: Statistical Data Analysis; Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning; Statistical Machine Learning; Symbolic Machine Learning; Probabilistic Graphical Models; Theory of Algorithms; Advanced Algorithms; Combinatorial Optimization; Graph Theory; Algorithmic Game Theory; Multi-agent Systems; Planning for Artificial Intelligence; Logical Reasoning and Programming; Artificial Intelligence in Robotics.

#### **Mother and Teacher Pontifical Catholic University (PUCMM)**

Santiago, Dominican Republic

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING - BE: ELECTRONICS AND AUTOMATION, 3.8 US GPA

2008 - 2013

• Topics: Embedded Systems; Power Electronics; Linear Control Theory; Biomedical Electronics; Linear Systems Analysis; Instrumentation.

# **Complementary Education**

#### Coursera (DeepLearning.AI)

Online

Machine Learning Engineering for Production (MLOps) Specialization

2021

• Topics: Data/Model/Deployment Pipelines; Managing ML Production Systems; Project Scoping and Design; Concept Drift; ML Metadata; Data Transformations/Validation; Fairness Indicators; Explainable Al; Baselines; Performance Analysis; Monitoring; ML Engineering for Production.

**Udacity** Online

COMPUTER VISION NANODEGREE

2021

• **Topics:** Image Recognition and Segmentation; CNNs/RNNs; Object Detection (YOLO, Faster R-CNN); Image Captioning; Object Motion and Tracking (motion models, video analysis); Optical Flow and Feature Matching; Robot Localization (Bayesian statistics); Graph SLAM.